A Finding Aid to the Elizabeth McCausland Papers, 1838-1995, bulk 1920-1960, in the Archives of American Art AAA.mccaeliz
Archives of American Art
- Other Research and Writing Files, 1896, 1926-1958; Series 7; 4.6 Linear feet Boxes 21-25, 31
  - Various Projects, 1896, 1926-1958; 7.4
    - "The Nude in American Art," 1953-1954 (Box 24, Folder 48-55)
    - "The Nude in American Art," 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 1-5)
    - "The Nude in American Art," Mary S. Abbot, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - The Photo League, Symposium on Functions of Photography, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Photography (Norman C. Lipton), 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 8-10)
    - "Picasso", 1944 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Poems of the Midwest, [1946] (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Questionnaires (Box 25)
      - "Art and Advertising" (Box 25)
        - Art Directors, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 13-14)
        - Painters, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 15-17)
        - Sculptors, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - "Why Can't America Afford Art?" (Box 25)
        - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 19)
        - Excerpts, [1945] (Box 25, Folder 20)
        - Findings, [1945] (Box 25, Folder 21)
        - Lists, [1945] (Box 25, Folder 22)
        - Miscellaneous, 1941, [1945] (Box 25, Folder 23)
        - Painters A-L, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 24-25)
        - Painters M-Z, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 26)
        - Sculptors, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 27)
        - Tabulations, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Quintanilla, Luis, 1938 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Radio Broadcast on Picasso, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Russian War Relief, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Sculpture, circa 1926-1958 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Selective Bibliography on American Painting by A. G. Weimer, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Springfield Museum of Fine Arts, 1934 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - The Springfield Republican, Notes on Articles, 1920s (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Stock, Joseph, 1932 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Ulmann, Doris, circa 1926-1958 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Walker Art Center, Everyday Art Gallery, 1945-1947 (Box 25, Folder 39-42)
    - War Department, "Contemporary American Painting" Exhibition, [1946] (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Wichita Art Museum, circa 1926-1958 (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Oversize, Three Card Index Files to Newspapers, circa 1926-1958 (Box 31)
- Subject Files, 1927-1954; Series 8; 1 Linear feet Boxes 25-26
  Series consists of files of clippings (including some clippings of McCausland's articles for The Springfield Republican), scattered notes and correspondence, photographs, and other printed material organized according to subject. Some files may have been collected as reference files. Others may relate to further research activities and interests of McCausland or possibly even to some unidentified research projects. Some files (mostly clippings of McCausland's articles on different artists and art topices) were loosely grouped together under the heading "Art and Social History" although it is unclear why or what this means.
  Subject files are arranged in alphabetical order.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned.
  - American Artists Group, 1935-1937 (Box 25, Folder 45)
  - The Architects, Painters, and Sculptors Collaborative, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 46)
  - Architecture, 1940-1950 (Box 25, Folder 47)
  - Art and Government, circa 1927-1954 (Box 25, Folder 48)
  - "Art and Social History" (Box 25)
    - American Roots, 1930-1937, 1950-1952 (Box 25, Folder 49)
    - Art in Wartime, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 50)
    - Art in Wartime/Art Under F.D.R., 1945 (Box 25, Folder 51-52)
    - Clippings, 1937-1946 (Box 25, Folder 53-55)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Negro Art, 1935 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Noguchi, Isamu, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1934-1937 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Siqueiros, David Alfara, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Social Content, 1933, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Soutine, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Steichen, Edward, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Stein, Gertrude, re: Modern Art, 1933-1935 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - World War II and Art, [1942] (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Art in Architecture (Box 26)
    - Murals, circa 1927-1954 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Sculpture, circa 1927-1954 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - "Art in War", 1941 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Art as Propaganda, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Associated American Artists, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Brainard, George, 1937 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Censorship, 1934-1937 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Collections, 1937 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Conference on Cultural Freedom and Civil Liberties, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Contemporary American Art, World's Fair, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Dance, 1933-1938 (Box 26, Folder 21-22)
  - Degas, Edgar, circa 1927-1954 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Design Laboratory, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Federal Art Project (Box 26)
    - History, 1935-1937 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Reports, 1936-1939 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Federal Art Project, 1939-1940 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Federal Arts Bill, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Film, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Film, Documentary, 1938-1940 (Box 26, Folder 30-32)
  - Homer, Winslow, 1937 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - Industrial Design, circa 1927-1954 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1943-1944 (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous, 1935-1942 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Mount, William Sidney, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1938-1939 (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - National War Poster Competition, circa 1927-1954 (Box 26, Folder 40)
  - National Wartime Conference, 1943 (Box 26, Folder 41-42)
  - New Bedford Strike, 1928 (Box 26, Folder 43)
  - New York World's Fair (1939), 1936-1938 (Box 26, Folder 44)
  - Notes, 1936-1937, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 45)
  - The Nude in Art, 1922 (Box 26, Folder 46)
  - "Outdoor Billboard Posters from South and Central America" Exhibition, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 47)
  - Photography, 1936-1952 (Box 26, Folder 48)
  - Picasso, Pablo, 1934-1937 (Box 26, Folder 49)
  - Post-War Planning, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 50)
  - Sacco and Vanzetti, 1927-1930 (Box 26, Folder 51-53)
  - Slides, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 54)
  - Soviet Union, 1939, 1944-1945 (Box 26, Folder 55)
  - Spain, 1934, [1937] (Box 26, Folder 56)
  - The Springfield Republican Lockout, 1935 (Box 26, Folder 57)
  - Stieglitz, Alfred, undated (Box 26, Folder 58)
  - Treasury Department, Section of Fine Arts, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 59)
  - Works Progress Administration, 1936-1938 (Box 26, Folder 60)
- Other Exhibition Files, 1939-1941, 1944; Series 9; 0.1 Linear feet Box 26
  Series consists of files relating to McCausland's work organizing various exhibitions, including "The World of Tomorrow" exhibition at The Berkshire Museum in the summer of 1939, the first comprehensive group exhibition of silk screen color prints at the Springfield Museum of Fine Arts in March 1940, another (perhaps related) group exhibition of silk screen color prints at the New York State Museum in the summer of 1940, and an exhibition of contemporary photography at the A.C.A. Gallery in August 1944. Files include correspondence, lists of works, text for wall labels and catalogs, and photographs. Files document McCausland's activities of selecting works, planning, and making arrangements for the exhibitions, and her interactions with others involved, such as Laura Bragg at The Berkshire Museum, Charles Adams at the New York State Museum, Audrey MacMahon at the Works Progress Administration, Edward Landon, and various artists.
  Files are arranged in alphabetical order. Items within files are arranged in rough chronological order, according to the existing organization. Related material can be found amongst research and writing files, and general correspondence.
  - A.C.A. Gallery, "Photography Today" Exhibition, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 61)
  - The Berkshire Museum, "The World of Tomorrow" Exhibition, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 62-64)
  - New York State Museum, Silk Screen Exhibition, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 65-66)
  - Springfield Museum of Fine Arts, Silk Screen Exhibition, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 67-69)
- Teaching Files, 1939-1965; Series 10; 0.5 Linear feet Box 27
  Series consists primarily of files relating to a course on American art history taught by McCausland at Barnard College during the spring and fall semesters of 1956. Files include course material, lectures, notes, correspondence, and printed material. Also found are scattered files relating to a course on culture morphology or the morphology of design at the Laboratory School of Industrial Design in 1939; a course, or series of lectures, on American art and American life given at Cooper Union in 1952; her teaching stint at Sarah Lawrence College in the early 1940s; and a planned course on American art at the University of Southern California during the summer session of 1965, which McCausland ultimately had to back out of due to illness.
  This series has been scanned in its entirety, except for one folder of publications.
  - Barnard College (Box 27)
    - Chronology of American Art, [1956] (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence and Miscellaneous, 1955-1957 (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
    - Course Information, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
    - Lectures, [1956] (Box 27, Folder 7-10)
    - Notes, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 11-14)
    - Publications, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Reading Lists, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Student Appraisals and Other Material, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Cooper Union, "American Art and American Life" Lectures 1-6, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 18-19)
  - Laboratory School of Industrial Design, "Culture Morphology", 1939 (Box 27, Folder 20-26)
  - Sarah Lawrence College, circa 1942 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - University of Southern California, 1964-1965 (Box 27, Folder 28)
- Committee Files, 1936-1960; Series 11; 0.5 Linear feet Box 27
  Series consists of files relating to McCausland's involvement in various artist committees and associations, and art organizations. Included are files stemming from her work on the Promotion Committee of the New York City Council for Art Week, which was involved in planning National Art Week 1940 and sought to promote the purchase of art by the general public; and on the Advisory Committee on Photography at the Museum of Modern Art, on which she served with Ansel Adams and Paul Strand, among others. Also found are files stemming from her participation in the Artists League of America, organizing the Critics Group and planning a national conference on artists in the war; in the Artists Societies for National Defense, which was a collective of art organizations dedicated to developing a program for the use of art in national defense; and on the Writers War Board of the Author's League, which held a meeting on "The American Arts Work for the War" in May 1942. There are also some general files on art organizations and on McCausland's community interests and political activities. Files typically include minutes, reports, correspondence, notes, writings, and printed material.
  - American Artists Congress, 1936-1941 (Box 27, Folder 29-31)
  - American Labor Party, 1942 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Art Organizations, 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Artists League of America, 1942 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Artists Societies for National Defense, 1941-1942 (Box 27, Folder 35-38)
  - Community Interests, 1941 (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - International Association of Art Critics (Box 27)
    - American Section, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - A Report on Artists in the United States, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 41)
  - League of American Writers, 1942 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - Museum of Modern Art, Advisory Committee on Photography, 1944-1945 (Box 27, Folder 43)
  - New York City Council for Art Week, Promotion Committee, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 44-45)
  - Political Activities, 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 46-47)
  - United American Artists, 1936-1940 (Box 27, Folder 48)
  - Writers War Board of the Authors League, 1942 (Box 27, Folder 49)
- Printed Material, 1923-1953; Series 12; 4.6 Linear feet Boxes 28-32, 34, OV 38, BV 44-47
  Series consists of extensive clipping files, scrapbooks, and volumes of McCausland's articles and columns that appeared in The Springfield Republican from 1923 to 1946, along with some other printed material including reprints of some of McCausland's magazine articles, books, clippings on McCausland, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and publications.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  12.1: Articles and Columns for The Springfield Republican, 1923-1946
  12.2: Other Printed Material, 1929-1953
  The clippings of articles and columns for The Springfield Republican in sub-series 12.1 have not been scanned, except for five scrapbooks of clippings and 2 folders of clippings about "The Blue Menace" and Picasso. The Bound Volumes of clippings are too large to be scanned. Many of these same clippings are scattered throughout the Subject Files in Series 8. Much of sub-series 12.2, Other Printed Material, has been scanned, except for books, a few publications, and exhibition wall labels, as noted in the folder titles.
  - Articles and Columns for The Springfield Republican, 1923-1946; 12.1
    - Scrapbooks of Clippings (Box 28)
      - Scrapbook, December 1923-January 1925 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Scrapbook, January 1925-April 1926 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Scrapbook, April 1926-April 1927 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Scrapbook, April 1927-November 1928 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Scrapbook, November 1928-March 1929 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Clippings (Box 29)
      - Vacation Issues, 1927-1929 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - "The Blue Menace", 1928 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Clippings, 1928? (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Clippings, 1928 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Feature Articles, 1929-1934 (Box 29, Folder 5-6)
      - Clippings, 1929 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Clippings, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 8-9)
      - Clippings, 1931 (Box 29, Folder 10-11)
      - Clippings, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 12-13)
      - Clippings, 1933 (Box 29, Folder 14-15)
      - Picasso, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 16-17)
      - Clippings, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 18-19)
      - Clippings, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 20-21)
      - Film Criticism, 1936-1939 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Clippings, 1936 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Clippings, 1937 (Box 30, Folder 3-4)
      - Clippings, 1938 (Box 30, Folder 5-6)
      - Latin-American Art, 1939-1943 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Clippings, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 8-9)
      - Clippings, 1940 (Box 30, Folder 10-11)
      - Clippings, 1941 (Box 30, Folder 12-13)
      - Clippings, 1942 (Box 30, Folder 14-15)
      - Clippings, 1943 (Box 30, Folder 16-17)
      - Clippings, 1944 (Box 30, Folder 18-19)
      - Clippings, 1945 (Box 30, Folder 20-21)
      - Clippings, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 22-23)
      - Clippings, circa 1928-1946 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Tear Sheets of Art Column, 1935-1936 (Box BV 44)
    - Tear Sheets of Art Column, 1937-1938 (Box BV 45)
    - Tear Sheets of Art Column, 1939-1940 (Box BV 46)
    - Tear Sheets of Art Column, 1941-1942 (Box BV 47)
  - Other Printed Material, 1929-1953; 12.2
    - Announcements and Press Releases, 1940-1947 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Art Reproductions, circa 1929-1953 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Articles by McCausland, 1937-1947 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Books, 1929, 1943, 1946, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      Oversized items in Box 31
    - Clippings on McCausland, 1935-1953 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, Miscellaneous, circa 1929-1953 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Clippings (originally from a scrapbook?), 1933-1940 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - "Eight Studies by Mexican Masters of Graphic Arts", 1952 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      Oversized items in OV 38
    - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1936-1946 (Box 32, Folder 9)
      Oversized items in Box 34
    - Invitations, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1931-1951 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - New School Bulletin and Course Information, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Programs, 1934-1951 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Publications, 1936-1953 (Box 32, Folder 14-16)
    - Wall Labels, undated (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Oversize, Books, 1929, 1943, 1946, 1950 (Box 31)
    - Oversize, Exhibition Announcement, 1946 (Box 34)
      Scanned with Box 32, Folder 9
    - Oversize, Wall Labels, undated (Box 34)
    - Oversize, "Eight Studies by Mexican Masters of Graphic Arts", 1952 (Box OV 38)
      Scanned with Box 32, Folder 8
- Photographs, circa 1905-1950; Series 13; 1.4 Linear feet Boxes 32-36, OV 37
  Series consists of photographs of artists and works of art, photographs as art, and prints from photography exhibitions at The Museum of Modern Art collected by McCausland in the course of her wide-ranging research and writing activities. Of particular note amongst the photographs as art are those taken by Berenice Abbott from 1935 to 1938 as part of a WPA project to document the city and published as a book, Changing New York (1939), with commentary by McCausland. Of particular note amongst the photographs of artist are ones of Isamu Noguchi working on his "News" plaque for the Associated Press Building at Rockefeller Center circa 1938-1940. Also found are some photographs of McCausland, including one with Gertrude Stein taken in 1934 (the original of which is missing).
  Included in many of the photograph files are copy prints and negatives made by the Archives.
  Files are arranged in alphabetical order. Photographs can also be found amongst research and writing files.
  This series has been scanned in its entirety, except for duplicates and negatives.
  - Farm Security Administration Photographs, circa 1930-1950 (Box 32, Folder 18-19)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1950 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Photographs as Art (Box 32)
    - Abbott, Berenice, "Changing New York", 1935-1937 (Box 32, Folder 21)
      Oversized items in Box 35
    - Brainard, George B., circa 1930-1950 (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Gardner, Alex, circa 1930-1950 (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Libsohn, Sol, circa 1939 (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1950 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Morgan, Barbara, "Celebration, 1940 (Box 32, Folder 26)
      Oversized items in Box 36
    - Warren, DeWitt, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - Weegee, circa 1918, 1944 (Box 32, Folder 28)
      Oversized items in Box 36 and OV 37
    - Weston, Edward, "Dunes at Oceano, CA", circa 1937 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Photographs of Artists (Box 33 (hol))
    - Edmondson, William (Photographer: Louise Dahl Wolfe), [1937] (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Kroll, Leon, circa 1930-1950 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Noguchi, Isamu, [1938-1940] (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Picasso, Pablo (Photographer: Man Ray), circa 1930-1950 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Photograph of Elizabeth McCausland and Gertrude Stein (original missing), 1934 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Elizabeth McCausland (Box 33)
    - Childhood, circa 1905-1908 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Portraits, circa 1916-1945 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - New Mexico, 1941 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - At Her Printing Press (Photographer: Berenice Abbott), circa 1935 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - At Various Openings and Gatherings, circa 1937-1950 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Silk Screen Demonstrations, World's Fair, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - At Home in New York, circa 1945 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Works of Art (Box 33)
    - European, circa 1930-1950 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Federal Art Project, 1938-1939 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Government Buildings, circa 1930-1950 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Gregory, Waylande, circa 1930-1950 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1950 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Mount, William Sidney, circa 1930-1950 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - National Defense Posters, 1941, 1943 (Box 33, Folder 19-20)
    - New York World's Fair, [1939] (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Prints from Photography Exhibitions at The Museum of Modern Art, 1937-1945 (Box 33, Folder 22-24)
  - Oversize, Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1950 (Box 34)
    Scanned with Box 32, Folder 20
  - Oversize, Picasso Pablo (Photographer: Man Ray), circa 1930-1950 (Box 34)
    Scanned with Box 33, Folder 4
  - Oversize, Abbott, Berenice, "Changing New York", 1935-1937 (Box 35)
    Scanned with Box 32, Folder 21
  - Oversize, Morgan, Barbara, "Celebration", 1940 (Box 36)
    Scanned with Box 32, Folder 26
  - Oversize, Weegee, 1944 (Box 36)
    Scanned with Box 32, Folder 28
  - Oversize, Weston, Edward, "Dunes at Oceano, CA", circa 1937 (Box 36)
    Scanned with Box 32, Folder 29
  - Oversize, Edmundson, William (Photographer: Louise Dahl Wolfe), [1937] (Box 36)
    Scanned with Box 33, Folder 1
  - Oversize, Weegee, circa 1918 (Box OV 37)
- Art Work, 1887-1942; Series 14; 0.7 Linear feet Boxes 33-34, OV 39-43
  Series consists of art work (many are signed) either given to McCausland by the artist or collected by her in the course of her work as an art critic and art historian. Art work includes drawings and watercolors by Max Bohm, Adolf Aldrich, Frank Buffmire (documenting McCausland's contributions to the American Processional exhibition, on which she worked in 1950), Edward Landon, Art Young, and others. Also found are prints by Asa Cheffetz, Elizabeth Olds, and David Rose, as well as silk screen calendars, another calendar of prints (signed by some of the artists), and a folio of prints by the Artists' Union of Western Massachusetts. There is also an acrylic painting attributed to L. Jean Liberte.
  Art work is also found among the research files on Alfred Maurer.
  - Drawings by Max Bohm, 1887-1888 (Box 33, Folder 25)
    Oversized items in OV 39
  - Drawings, Figure Studies (Artist Unknown), circa 1920-1942 (Box 33, Folder 26)
    Oversized items in OV 40
  - Drawings by Various Artists, circa 1920-1942 (Box 33, Folder 27)
    Oversized items in OV 41
  - Painting (attributed to L. Jean Liberte), circa 1920-1942 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - Prints (Box 33)
    - By Various Artists, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 29)
      Oversized items in OV 42
    - Silk Screen Calendars, 1941-1942 (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - "A Folio of Prints by the Artists' Union of Western Massachusetts", circa 1920-1942 (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - "Victory 1942, A Calendar and Sixteen Prints for Democracy" (Box 33, Folder 32)
      With prints signed by artists Joe Leboit, Elizabeth Olds, Hugo Gellert, Jim Egleson, Hilda Robbins, Art Young, and Harry Gottlieb.
  - Watercolors by Various Artists, 1933 (Box 33, Folder 33)
    Oversized items in OV 43
  - Oversize, Silk Screen Calendars, 1941-1942 (Box 34)
    Scanned with Box 33, Folder 30
  - Oversize, Drawings by Max Bohm, 1887-1888 (Box OV 39)
    Scanned with Box 33, Folder 25
  - Oversize, Drawings, Figure Studies (Artist Unknown), circa 1920-1942 (Box OV 40)
    Scanned with Box 33, Folder 26
  - Oversize, Drawings by Various Artists, circa 1920-1942 (Box OV 41)
    Scanned with Box 33, Folder 27
  - Oversize, Painting (attributed to L. Jean Liberte), circa 1920-1942 (Box OV 41)
    Scanned with Box 33, Folder 28
  - Oversize, Prints by Various Artists, 1940 (Box OV 42)
    Scanned with Box 33, Folder 29
  - Oversize, Watercolors by Various Artists, 1933 (Box OV 43)
    Scanned with Box 33, Folder 33
- Elizabeth McCausland Material from the Estate of Berenice Abbott, 1920-1995; Series 15; 5.4 Linear feet Boxes 48-53